technology is powerful it's also risky
when we create it together it is less
risky and more powerful so in this video
we are going to cover the things that we
can do with technology together that no
single technology company designed for
profit and owned by a tiny few can even
hope to accomplish you can imagine if we
owned facebook together how powerful
that would be that we could improve it
we could make sure we we trust the
information we would put the systems in
place to make sure we're fact-checking
in a way that doesn't stifle free speech
make sure that we're keeping people safe
now we don't own Facebook nor are we
going to own Facebook we can recreate
something very facebook like and own it
together even if we just had facebook
that would be amazing but there are
things that we can do together when we
own it together and design it together
that they will never be able to do and
therefore we out-compete them hands-down
they have to convince us that they're
working more in our Benner benefit than
in our disadvantage right that they they
give us more than they cost us and it's
starting to show they're costing us a
lot they're selling our data they're
costing us elections they're doing
things that are the outcome of seeking
profit and the outcome of just not
knowing what to do about it not being
able to be transparent about it when we
create something together we empower our
members to help us improve it tell us
what you don't trust so we can make it
more trustworthy tell us what doesn't
make sense in the transparency of
information so we can make it make
better sense to you tell us what
features would help you be empowered and
using this technology more or is it
hurting your life because you're
addicted to it how can we help your life
be better how can we create it in a way
where it doesn't have that overarching
power over your life we're creating for
our membership which means we're not
creating to make sure you're spending
eight hours a day on social media for
creating the tools to be able to help
you live your best life as an individual
by asking you and empowering you to help
co-create the tools that help you live
your best life we can create something
so powerful because we trust it with a
system that invites you to share your
medical information in a safe way
including your genetic information your
environmental information and your
current health status and the treatments
that you choose to seek together with
our collective information one person's
data isn't going to cure cancer one-off
scientific studies aren't going to cure
cancer but the plethora of information
we can create and utilize together we
can cure cancer we can cure Alzheimer's
or at least drastically reduce the
instances that occur the only way to do
that is for it to be voluntary and
trustworthy and safe for-profit
companies aren't going to be able to do
that there is so much information we
need to be able to tackle the complex
interconnected problems we face right
now the environmental problems the
social problems our personal problems
our health problems all of that is going
to require a cooperative it's the only
way to do it the only way we solve all
of these complex issues is together with
the system we trust and can understand
as individuals and we do that by
continually looking to improve it how if
you don't trust it what would get you to
trust it if it doesn't make sense
you what would make it make sense to you
those things are built into the
cooperative model and they are exactly
what we can do that Facebook and Google
and Apple and Amazon can't and with that
we out-compete the tech giants because
they can't do what we are gonna do doing
technology together in a way where we're
constantly improving it and looking to
support it looking to make it better for
ourselves and everybody else it's more
powerful than anything they can create
thank you please like and subscribe